Kayssé Rachid . Jarvis Consulting

I am Kayssé Rachid, a dedicated software engineer with a BEng in Software Engineering from Concordia University. My professional journey has seen me take on pivotal roles such as a Full-Stack Developer/SCRUM Master at Elance DEI, a Backend Developer Intern at CLE, and a Full-Stack Developer Intern at Nakisa. I specialize in Full-Stack development with technologies such as Java Spring, React, Vue.js and SQL databases.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Spring / SpringBoot, JUnit, C#, JavaScript, React, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL), Scrum/Agile, Git,

REST APIs

Competent: Python, Node.js, Vue.js, CI/CD, Cloud Azure

Familiar: NoSQL (MongoDB), C++, C, Angular, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Linux

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_KaysseRachid

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Designed a Linux cluster to monitor and collect hardware specification data and resource usage data from Linux servers. The project is implemented using various technologies such as Bash scripts for data collection, PostgreSQL for data storage, Docker for containerization, and Git for version control.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Grep App: Implemented a Java application that simulates Linux grep command which allows users to search matching strings from a file.
- JDBC App: Developed a trading platform REST API calling Alpha Vantage API to gather the latest stock information

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not StartedSpark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

Highlighted Projects

ServiceHub: During my university capstone project, developed a web application allowing customers to book professional services, and workers to advertise their service across Montreal and its surroundings. Implemented the backend using C# and following the CQRS architecture, the frontend with React, and persisted the data with a PostgreSQL database.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (June 2024 - Present): Working on various projects as a Jarvis Consultant, such as a Linux Cluster Monitor App, a Java Grep App to perform Linux grep commands and a Java Stock App that retrieves the latest stock market data from an API.

Full-Stack Developer / SCRUM Master, Elance DEI (May 2023 - December 2023): Designed features from end-to-end for an HR learning platform, created and managed the development and production pipelines in Azure, and led Agile development processes.

Backend Developer Intern, CLE (December 2022 - March 2023): Developed microservices for a reservation platform, improved API Gateway implementation, and achieved high test coverage with NUnit.

Full-Stack Developer Intern, Nakisa (May 2022 - August 2022): Developed features for a B2B Real Estate application using Java Spring and Vue.js. Facilitated real-time tracking and management, and implemented testing for each feature that I worked on.

Education

Concordia University (2018-2022), Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering

Miscellaneous

- Soccer friendly league
- Reading
- Travelling (only 1 continent left to visit)